So the inspiration for our little project here,
لذلك كان مصدر إلهام مشروعنا الصغير هنا،
was this Rotten Tomatoes top 100 movies of all time list. How do we get it.
هو قائمة أفضل 100 فيلم على الإطلاق في موقع ويب Rotten Tomatoes. كيف نحصل على ذلك.
Rotten Tomatoes doesn't give us a file to download unfortunately.
للأسف لا يمنحنها موقع ويبRotten Tomatoes ملفًا لتنزيله.
For this lesson, I'm just going to give it to you.
وفي هذا الدرس، سأعطيه لك وحسب.
Gathering can be complicated,
قد يكون التجميع معقدًا،
but it can also be extremely easy.
ولكنه يمكن أن يكون سهلًا للغاية أيضًا.
Sometimes you are simply just given a file.
في بعض الأحيان تحصل على أحد الملفات وحسب.
I've pre-gathered this dataset with its four columns; rank, title, rating,
لقد قمت مسبقاً بتجميع مجموعة البيانات هذه بأعمدتها الأربعة؛ الفئة والعنوان والتصنيف
and number of reviews, and it's 101 rows,
وعدد المراجعات، وهي 101 صف،
one for the headers and one for each of the top 100 movies.
واحد لعناوين الأعمدة والآخر لكل فيلم من أفضل 100 فيلم.
I put the data in a flat file called a TSV file which stands for tab separated values.
كما قمت بوضع البيانات في ملف ثابت يسمى ملف TSV يرمز إلى قيم مفصولة بعلامات جدولة.
There's a link for you to download it in the classroom.
ويوجد رابط لتحميل ذلك الملف في الفصل الدراسي.
Picture this as me e-mailing this file to you,
قم بتصوير هذا عندما أرسل لك هذا الملف عبر البريد الإلكتروني
or giving it to you on a thumb drive,
أو عندما أقدمه إليك من خلال محرك أقراص مصغر
or you accessing the file from your company's file storage system.
أو الحصول على الملف من خلال نظام تخزين الملفات الخاص بالشركة.
So point and click and download it, and we'll move on.
لذا قم بالتحديد وانقر عليه وقم بتنزيله، وسنواصل.
We don't need to do it programmatically in this case,
في هذه الحالة، لا نحتاج إلى القيام بذلك برمجيًا
because we'll assume that this data is internal,
لأننا سنفترض أن هذه البيانات داخلية،
and can't be downloaded from the Internet.
ولا يمكن تنزيلها من الإنترنت.
You're going to learn about the structure of flat files next.
وفيما يلي ستتعرف على بنية الملفات الثابتة.